

## **PROFILE**

5+ years experienced and passionate web developer focused on crafting great web experiences.

Creation and innovation have been my area of interest since I started working with web technologies.

Worked on 30+ web applications with collaboration of the creative team. Also efficient as an individual contributor to manage end to end development process.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML/CSS jQuery Bootstrap 5 React

Redux Node Express MongoDB

WordPress Laravel Bitbucket

#### **EDUCATION**

**B.Tech in Computer Science**West Bengal University of Technology
Batch of 2013

**Higher Secondary**Maheshtala High School
Batch of 2009

Secondary Nangi High School Batch of 2007

# **CONTACT**

Call: +91 855 311 0237

Email: sbhblore1@gmail.com

Location: Bangalore

Website: https://iamshubhajit.github.io/

# SHUBHAJIT HALDER

# **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Senior Analyst** – Clarivate Analytics (Formerly DRG) / Oct 2018 – Present Joined the marketing team as an analyst and web developer to manage the front end of the company's corporate websites.

- Assists the campaign owners with creative page design ideas and implementations.
- Developed single page application for company's product dashboard using React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, jQuery. Worked on custom functional components, React hooks, various libraries like Axios, React-router-dom and Redux. Implemented drag and drop file upload feature using React Drop-zone-ui.
- Worked on backend with Node js and MongoDB to develop APIs. Implemented login feature with passport-local. Also has exposer to passport-google-oAuth2
- Developed an automated newsletter creation tool for the customer experience team using Core PHP/MySQL, HTML, CSS, jQuery which reduced 80% production efforts of the newsletters. Implemented feature to download the newsletter in .html format which can be directly used in Pardot email marketing tool.
- Experienced in Bitbucket for code management and version control.

# Web Developer - Skhema / Jan 2017 - Sept 2018

Joined as the in-charge of the company's web development business and worked as an individual contributor in more than 10 projects including in-house applications.

- In-charge of the end to end management of all projects.
- Converted one website into mobile app using PhoneGap.

# Assistant Web Developer - Wolabi Solutions / Feb 2015 - Oct 2016

Started career with Wolabi as a full stack web developer and worked in more than 20 various web applications.

- In-charge of the architecture and UI/UX of all the projects. Gave training to new recruits on project specific web technologies.
- Developed a t-shirt designing tool with extensive features for a garments printing brand with Laravel, MySql, HTML, CSS, jQuery and Fabric.js.
- Worked on mobile recharge and payment APIs to develop an online recharge application.

### **BRAINCHILD**

Currently developing a single page application which contains a full-featured social-media and end to end project management system which can be used by any organization for internal use.

- Developing frontend using React, Redux and React-Bootstrap. Using Node Js and Express for the APIs with MongoDB as the database.
- Developed a comment-mention plugin for the project management for better UX.
- Implemented infinite scroll, sticky sidebar, cropped image upload for the social media.
- Used React-TinyMCE as the WYSIWYG HTML editor for the articles and posts.